<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Choss Bucket</title>
    <description>Just some climbing in Europe</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 17:08:50 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 17:08:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Aiguille du Tour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We got the cable car up to give us a boost on our walk to the Albert Premier hut, this was the last day the cars were running and the last night we could stay in the hut, luckily the weather had decided it was going to be beautiful just in time. The walk up was lovely, much easier than we had found it last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We attempted this route last year and were foiled by a hungry fox who came in the night to steal all our food. This year however we were fitter and better prepared. And we didn’t carry our bivvy gear up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150920_141844.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to the hut in time for a coffee and then went down to the glacier to check out the route, we would be going in the dark in the early morning so needed to get our bearings. In order to make it easier for ourselves, and because it was fun, we made some cairns to add to the others to guide ourselves on to the glacier the following morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150920_163704.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cairns&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the hut the boy admired the osb, which to his delight, was everywhere. *nb. the crocs are mandatory in the huts, not our preferred style of footwear*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150920_150058.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;osb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Albert 1er has a room where people not eating the food cooked by the guardians can cook which is pretty nice really as it meant we didn’t have to go out into the cold to cook and ate with the other guests. Just after dinner the sun was setting over the mountains on the opposite side of the valley and the clouds had setteled just below their peaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150920_200509.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;clouds and sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got up at 5am after a terrible nights sleep in a room with 8 other people, 3 of them slightly overweight smoking men. I will say no more. We walked out on to the rocky terrain behind the hut and with the help of our cairns (and many others) we were on the glacier within half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_054912.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;headtorch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a magical hour on the glacier lit by headtorch with the sun slowly coming up and revealing the aiguille du chardonnay to our right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_164957.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;chardonay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_071539.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sunrise&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Route finding was easy as there was a good track, although this was our first encounter with a wet glacier and some of the exposed crevasses were big. We were roped up 15m apart (our earlier coil taking practice paid off somewhat here) but walking round corners across snow bridges was slightly scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_070449.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;crevass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here we walked up a steep col and out into the sunlight on the trient glacier. It’s difficult to put into words how amazing this was, there was no one else here (we were the first party out on a quiet day), the sun had just risen and there was nothing but mountains and snow in every direction. After shedding a layer we continued on to the rocky scrable up to the summit of the aiguille du tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_080132.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;trient glacier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the bergshrund and went up on to a little path before scrambling up to the summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_081846.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bergshrund&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_082320.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;snow track&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_093800.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;scramble&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A guided party who we shared a room with last night got to the top when we were there which meant there was someone to take the all important summit photo for us! The guide who we had chatted to in the hut the night before was enthusiastic about us and said we moved well together which obviously made us basically swell with pride…he then suggested we have a go at the forbes arete on chardonnay, and now the boy will talk of nothing else!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the glacier the enthusiastic guide was nice enough to take a photo of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_095514.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;on the glacier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long walk down beckoned and we walked back across the glaciers to the hut where we got to go in the winter hut which was now open for the season. It was very cold inside!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150922_090319.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;glacier walk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walk down was long and tiring, our mountain boots are not made for walking long distances! We also got caught up in some sort of sheep and goat migration, and given our previous experience with goats we were a little nervous around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/aiguilledutour/IMG_20150921_140106.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;goats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it was completely fine and we made it down to the van eventually and got chatting to a woman who was just completing a 4 week walk through the alps and was treating herself to a night in a hotel in chamonix. We gave her a lift into town and treated ourselves, not quite so extravagantly, to hot showers and a campsite for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/21/aigiulle-du-tour.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/21/aigiulle-du-tour.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ice climbing on the Mer de Glace</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Chamonix on Monday morning and quickly made plans for our next adventure. We wanted to climb the index, a multi-pitch route in the aiguilles rouge. The weather looked good and we packed our bags to walk in on Tuesday, bivy, then climb the route, and another if time allowed, on Wednesday. Unfortunately when Tuesday arrived we checked the weather one last time and there were now 50kmph winds predicted up in the hills. Not ideal climbing conditions, but we consoled ourselves with some crag climbing at Les Galliands, it has amazing views of mont blanc and aiguille du midi even when its cloudy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/merdeglace/20150915_151353_Richtone(HDR).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;aiguille du midi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we decided to test out our new crampons and try a bit of easy ice climbing on the Mer de Glace. It’s pretty easy to get there, the Montenvers train runs up every half an hour, and although it was raining we decided we would go up anyway. There are lots of ladders down on to the glacier and it’s about a 20 minute walk from there until we were on the glacier properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/merdeglace/IMG_20150916_143853.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ladders&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a few places to test out our crampons, not the roped climbing we were hoping for, more like ice bouldering and ice traversing, but still fun and less hassle than setting up a top rope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/merdeglace/IMG_20150917_192136.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ice climbing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had a go at making an v thread in the ice which you could technically abseil off, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/merdeglace/IMG_20150917_185814.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ice thread&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rain cleared up towards midday and we had a walk up the glacier to look at the moraine, even though we been here the year before it had changed quite dramatically already, but was still incredibly beautiful. We could just about make out the impressive grand jorasses in the background too, perhaps one for next time…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/merdeglace/IMG_20150917_192025.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;morain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/16/Mer-De-Glace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/16/Mer-De-Glace.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Geneva</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So we did something unusual. We went sightseeing in Geneva, and we slept in an apartment, in an actual bed! It was great. My uncle works in an international school in Geneva, he put us up for the weekend and showed us the sights!&lt;br /&gt;
We went for cheese fondue on the lake, totally amazing, if incredibly rich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture/IMG_20150912_194940.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fondue&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to see neil hannon of the divine comedy play which was really nice, haven’t seen any live music since we’ve been out here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture/IMG_20150912_215444.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;neil hannon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we went to the museum of ethnography, we only went to the free bit but it kept us entertained whilst my uncle planned next weeks lessons. There were some great examples of old musical instruments, clothing from around the world, as well as a 25 meter screen playing rolling crashing waves. It didn’t seem to fit in with anything around it but it was nice to look at!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture/IMG_20150913_122155.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;waves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried to go to cern but it turns out that the visitor center is closed until may next year so we headed over to the united nations building and then the botanical gardens before getting the boat taxi back for a curry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture/IMG_20150913_165501.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;un&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture/IMG_20150913_152810.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;seating&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture/IMG_20150913_172047.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;glass house&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture/IMG_20150913_181245.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sculpture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture/IMG_20150913_184658.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;boat taxi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/12/Geneva.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/12/Geneva.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Night Time In Bregaglia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nightTimeBregaglia/DSF2255.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;julian pass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nightTimeBregaglia/DSF2261.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;night van&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nightTimeBregaglia/DSF2270.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;climbing in the dark&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/09/Night-Time-In-Bregaglia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/09/Night-Time-In-Bregaglia.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vergine - Al Gal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We had been waiting for a while for the weather to be good enough for us to get up into the mountains. It had snowed two days earlier but this route is east facing so we thought it would probably be OK now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/verginealgal/IMG_20150906_233555.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;topo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got the cable car up to the albigna dam, well worth the CHF18! The views over the dam and the mountains were amazing, and on the walk up we saw an ermine, very very cute and inquisitive, clearly checking us out before scampering away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/verginealgal/effect-express1441650381174.png&quot; alt=&quot;albigna lake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our German guidebook indicates that it should take 50 minutes from the cable car but it took us about 1 hour 20 mins, I think we are pretty slow walkers. When we arrived at the base of the climb we were looking for the start (obviously), the route begins right on the corner, not part of the way in from the left side as the topo suggests. I’m having doubts about this very expensive guidebook. Anyway there’s an red arrow painted on a rock showing the start of the route. There were also a few, very sparse bolts, reassuring as we knew we were on route.&lt;br /&gt;
We alternated leads which was more fun for me and a bit less stressful for the boy who usually leads most things, especially in the mountains. It was really good climbing, very enjoyable, but I got really cold at the summit and shivered about getting my big jacket on and eating a sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/verginealgal/effect-express1441649710823.png&quot; alt=&quot;summit pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We abbed down and hurried back into the sunlight. Just after we had got back to the stuff we left at the bottom the party above us dislodged a terrifyingly big rock right where we had been just 5 minutes earlier. Helmets would not have offered any protection :/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/verginealgal/IMG_20150907_135823.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;abb tat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/verginealgal/effect-express1441650214080.png&quot; alt=&quot;abseil&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the sun!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/verginealgal/IMG_20150907_145850.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;me at base of climb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/07/Vergine-Al-Gal-Traverse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/07/Vergine-Al-Gal-Traverse.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The door is fixed!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We had bumped into this German couple at a few crags and then at a cafe where we got chatting. After a pizza and a few coffees we spoke about our rucksack bouldering mat and the fact that our back door was broken. Turns out Wolfgang is a bit of a mechanical whizz and after about half an hour he had the door open, as well as showing us what to do if it happens again. Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/doorisfixed/IMG_20150905_182952.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fixed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/doorisfixed/IMG_20150905_185153.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fixed 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically prepare for lots of smug van photos with both back doors open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/doorisfixed/effect-express1441650142132.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;smug&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/06/The%20door%20is%20fixed!.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/06/The%20door%20is%20fixed!.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gallivaggio and Camping Aquafraggia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided that to improve our ropework some multipitch sport routes would be ideal, and as it turns out the ones at Gallavaggio were really good.  We were impressed with our speedy selves and managed to get to the top much faster than we thought we could, the training is working! Multi pitch sport is pretty fun, none of the stress of trad or the slog of mountains, but admittedly the views are not &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; as good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallavaggio/IMG_20150905_224739.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;topo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallavaggio/IMG_20150906_132725.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;climbing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallavaggio/effect-express1441649945117.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;top out&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we scrambled up the river, relaxed and read our books. And had a swim, obviously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallavaggio/effect-express1441649839804.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;waterfall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also visited the aquafraggia campsite and the guy who runs it has drawn loads of lovely topos in a huge book that is out for people to look at. He’s also put versions of them all up &lt;a href=&quot;http://campingacquafraggia.com/climbindex_en.htm&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; for free. The topo above is one of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallavaggio/IMG_20150905_210047.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;topo drawing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallavaggio/IMG_20150905_210100.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;topo drawing 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/06/Gallivaggio.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/06/Gallivaggio.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Waiting for a weather window</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We want to climb a few things up in the mountains so we need to wait for good conditions. There’s also loads to climb down in the valley, when it’s not raining. Luckily its still pretty here even when the weather is dismal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/weatherwindow/IMG_20150902_103742.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;clouds and mountains&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It only rained for a couple of days but there had been snow in the mountains and the odd bit of overnight rain meant that conditions weren’t ideal. We spent some time sport climbing at sasso del drago over in italy (where its is SO much cheaper to buy food). This place is great for a quick climb, roadside and dries quickly so when other crags were still suffering with seepage this one was dry. Good range of climbs from 4a to 8a. There are great topos on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://campingacquafraggia.com/climbindex_en.htm&quot;&gt;aquafraggia website&lt;/a&gt; for this crag and loads of other routes in the area as well as some of the mountains. We had a great days bouldering too, slightly precarious though as I broke the back door of the van the day we left, which meant that our ingenious bouldering mat slot now traps the bouldering mat inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/weatherwindow/IMG_20150717_140856.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;van in progress&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is part way through our build when the bouldering mat slot, on the left, was a great idea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we had to use our rucksacks, a disappointing solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/weatherwindow/effect-express1441736509954.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;boulder park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/weatherwindow/IMG_20150901_120001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rucksacks as bouldering mats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/weatherwindow/IMG_20150901_115607.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bouldering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also been doing some training to get up more prepared for the mountains, timing ourselves taking coils and going on uphill walks to pretty waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/weatherwindow/20150904_102821.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;waterfall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/weatherwindow/20150905_122857.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;waterfall selfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/weatherwindow/effect-express1441650036914.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;waterfall 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/05/waiting-for-a-weather-window.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/05/waiting-for-a-weather-window.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swiss Lakes 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was SO lovely! We bought a hideously expensive guidebook, Graubunden, which is in german :/ but has great topos and covers a huge area. We chilled out by lake chazza and when we got too hot decided to swim to the little island just off the shore. We tested out the waterproofness of the camera with a full submerge and have decided that it’s trustworthy :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090875.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;hammock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090885.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;island&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090886.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;swim&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went for a climb just over the road (and up a steep path!) at plaun da lej. As we were sorting our gear out we decided that this was not the best carabiner for belaying…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/20150831_205753.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jiveassbelays&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climbing was great and the views from the top over the lake and mountains were amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090890.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;climbing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090893.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;climbing2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy cooked tea and i got to relax and watch the sunset over the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/IMG_20150901_104340.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sunsetlake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/swiss-lakes-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/swiss-lakes-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swiss Lakes 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to leave the dolomites as we weren’t enjoying the rock type and were keen to climb some mountains before it’s too late in the year. We drove to Switzerland and stopped off near our destination of Val Bregaglia in Sankt Moritz. It’s very posh! We walked round the lake and had a welcome swim after the long drive before finding a great place to park up further down the road. There are 3 lakes high up in the alps and we spent the night right on the shore. Waking up to these amazing views is may favourite thing about the van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_095930.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lakemorning&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the day relaxing, reading and swimming by the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_155314.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/P1090870.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;lake2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_155513.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;selfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on we went on to the next lake, lake silvaplana to watch the windsurfers. It was crazily windy, i guess that was why it was so busy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_165941.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kitesurfers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had another lovely spot where we cooked tea with another great view!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_165622.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;onthevan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/31/swiss-lakes-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/31/swiss-lakes-1.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
