<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Choss Bucket</title>
    <description>Just some climbing in Europe</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 22:00:33 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 22:00:33 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swiss Lakes 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was SO lovely! We bought a hideously expensive guidebook, Graubunden, which is in german :/ but has great topos and covers a huge area. We chilled out by lake chazza and when we got too hot decided to swim to the little island just off the shore. We tested out the waterproofness of the camera with a full submerge and have decided that it’s trustworthy :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090875.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;hammock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090885.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;island&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090886.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;swim&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went for a climb just over the road (and up a steep path!) at plaun da lej. As we were sorting our gear out we decided that this was not the best carabiner for belaying…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/20150831_205753.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jiveassbelays&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climbing was great and the views from the top over the lake and mountains were amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090890.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;climbing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/P1090893.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;climbing2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy cooked tea and i got to relax and watch the sunset over the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt2/IMG_20150901_104340.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sunsetlake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/swiss-lakes-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/swiss-lakes-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swiss Lakes 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to leave the dolomites as we weren’t enjoying the rock type and were keen to climb some mountains before it’s too late in the year. We drove to Switzerland and stopped off near our destination of Val Bregaglia in Sankt Moritz. It’s very posh! We walked round the lake and had a welcome swim after the long drive before finding a great place to park up further down the road. There are 3 lakes high up in the alps and we spent the night right on the shore. Waking up to these amazing views is may favourite thing about the van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_095930.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lakemorning&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the day relaxing, reading and swimming by the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_155314.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/P1090870.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;lake2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_155513.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;selfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on we went on to the next lake, lake silvaplana to watch the windsurfers. It was crazily windy, i guess that was why it was so busy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_165941.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kitesurfers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had another lovely spot where we cooked tea with another great view!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/swisslakespt1/20150830_165622.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;onthevan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/31/swiss-lakes-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/31/swiss-lakes-1.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marmot chamois</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We had firts heard, and then seen this marmot (or one of a group of marmots) at an entrance to a cave where some of the climbs are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/marmotcam/IMG_20150828_115054.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;marmotcave&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hadn’t managed to get a photo of it and the boy has this fancy camera that has a remote setting we can link to my tablet and the idea was to set the camera up on a tripod close to the cave entrance and then retreat to an unthreatening distance. We saw the marmot on the way down to the climbs so thought it would be a good time to set up the camera. We tried not to spook the marmot but it disappeared inside the cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/marmotcam/20150828_103546.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sneaky&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat around the corner from the camera but about 10 minutes later realised that the camera was being coveted by a group of pre-pubescent boys who were creeping up on it thinking no-one was around. They also clambered all over mamot rock which probably spooked it. We set up the camera again near us at another entrance we had seen the marmot at, and set the camera to take a photo every minute or so. With the camera just in sight we climbed for around an hour or so and then checked the photos. Nothing. We assumed the marmot had just left because we and the kids were too noisy so gave up, but when we walked around the back he was bloody looking at us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/marmotcam/IMG_20150828_114904.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;marmot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happily the next day i managed to get a couple of blurry snaps of the marmot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/marmotcam/P1090859.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;marmot2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/marmotcam/P1090860.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;marmot3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/29/marmot-cam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/29/marmot-cam.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rossi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Although we still were not sure about the dolomite rock we thought we should at least give one of the many multi-pitch routes in the dolomites a go. We settled on Rossi as it was well within our abilities grade wise but slightly more pitches than we’ve done before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rossi/IMG_20150827_075458.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rossi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We parked up close to the climb, one of the better things about the dolomites over val masino was the proximity of the climbs, no slogging for us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rossi/effect-express1440272183740.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;vanview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to move together for a few pitches like we had done so successfully on the sfinge. However there was nowhere to place gear so we faffed around and dropped our coils and basically wasted a bunch of time. We were caught up by an Italian guide and two kids (his? who knows?) and they clumsily overtook us. I have held no problem with being overtaken at ab points but the irritating thing here was that the guide was fast but the two kids behind him were slow which meant that we kept crossing paths, there was a tremendous amount of rope faff and the boy got held up at the crux because the youngest kid couldn’t do it. Ugh. Anyway we had a sandwich break and let them get on with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rossi/IMG_20150822_115600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;couplesclimb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rossi/IMG_20150823_120909.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rope&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top was interesting as the ab ring was not immediately obvious and after the boy built a belay and I climbed up the walk around the chamois terrace (sadly devoid of chamois) looked pretty sketchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rossi/IMG_20150822_134948.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;chamoisterrace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However when we got round to the places with shear drops they had chains to sling yourself too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rossi/IMG_20150822_140111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;chainedin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shared some abseils down with some friendly guys and went back to enjoy a coffee and the view from the back door of the van :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/27/rossi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/27/rossi.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Citta dei Sassi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The city of stones. We arrived in the rain and clouds and the next morning woke up to an amazing view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cittidelsassi/20150828_121114.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cittadeisassi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is loads of sport climbing pretty close to twhere we parked but not road-side so it feels more remote, especially with the dramatic setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cittidelsassi/IMG_20150828_114804.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rocks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our rockfax guide book is great for getting us to the area but I’m not convinced that it’s massively accurate. Luckily most of the climbs are labelled :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cittidelsassi/IMG_20150820_104128.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;climblabel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cittidelsassi/IMG_20150820_115105.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;climblabel2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a couple of days ticking off climbs and prepping to climb something a little higher. Not convinced that I like dolomite rock, i miss val masino and it’s grippy grippy granite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cittidelsassi/IMG_20150826_104301.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;climber&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/24/cityofstones.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/24/cityofstones.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mountain Passes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I fucking hate mountain passes. I know the view is all magnificant and whatever but it’s hard to concentrate on that when you’re teetering on the edge of oblivion, in a van you’re driving on the wrong side of the road, doing 3 point turns on hair pin bends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mountainpasses/effect-express1440017871166.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mountainpass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually that road was fine. It’s unrepresentative of the horror endured on the way up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However today we got caught up in a weird Polish charity rally on the way to the Dolomites and the atmosphere was very supportive, everyone was having a good time and no-one was pissed off that I was going too slow round the bends. We stopped near the top of the pass and had a chat to some of the guys and met a cyclist who had rode from Norway to Italy via Serbia! Legs of steel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mountainpasses/effect-express1440012307300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rally&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our van, hidden by rally cars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/22/mountain-passes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/22/mountain-passes.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deep water soloing at lake como</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We had gone through Naomis wild swimming book and had seen that one of the places had a “difficult” approach because to get to it you had to climb a short via ferratta. As we selfishly like swimming spots to ourselves and are reasonable climbers we headed over there. Not only was it a lovely quiet spot for swimming there were also sport routes on the edge of the lake and lots of places we could deep water solo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildswimmingatcomo/P1090733.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;jadedws&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildswimmingatcomo/P1090738.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;alfdws&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a great place to park by the lake with mystery wifi, we had no idea where it was coming from!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildswimmingatcomo/P1090809.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildswimmingatcomo/IMG_20150817_205749.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;view2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back the next day to do some roped climbing and decided to test out the waterproofness of the waterproof camera we found last year in the alps. We got a bit scared of putting it in the water though, which resulted in a near-drowning experience…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildswimmingatcomo/P1090797.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;drowningselfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not broken! Maybe we will go for full submerge next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/20/deep-water-soloing-at-lake-como.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/20/deep-water-soloing-at-lake-como.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nobs Adventures</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So our amazing friend Naomi and her lovely boyfriend Bob are traveling through Europe in their green adventure van, wild swimming their way from France to Italy and back again. We were going to try and meet up but it just so happened that our favourite town val masino was about a 30 min walk from one of the swims Naomi wanted to do the most. They arrived on an unfortunately rainy day and after admiring each other vans and talking about the compleixties of gas and solar we hid away at the local cafe. It did stop raining in the late afternoon so we decided to make a break for it and walk up to val d’mello where there is an amazing wild swimming spot. The boy and I had already been up there for a bit of an explore and it was ridiculously cold - glacial melt - but we didn’t swim for long as there were loads of people about but no-one else swimming and we felt like a bit of a spectacle. And we were cold.&lt;br /&gt;
Because we had walked up in big jackets we were pretty warm when we got there and because it had rained quite a lot in the last 24 hours the water was a (sort of) bearable temperature. We had quite a long swim, by val masino standards but it was still pretty chilly. Naomi has been blogging their wild swim adventures and I’ve nicked a couple of her photos, see the rest of the blog here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nobsadventures/P8141159.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;clouds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nobsadventures/P8141177.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;swimming&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got out it started to rain and the rain turned into a pretty heavy thunderstorm which meant we all got quite wet, again. Back at the vans we dried off and pulled up door to door to make dinner. Very cosy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nobsadventures/P8141193.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;getting-dried-and-dressed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nobsadventures/P8141194.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;thundestorm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nobsadventures/P1090729.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;door-to-door&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/17/Nobs-Adventures.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/17/Nobs-Adventures.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wild Swimming In Italy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221404.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221404.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221424.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221424.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221431.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221431.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221502.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221502.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221520.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221520.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221541.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221541.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221601.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221601.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221648.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221648.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221701.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221701.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221708.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221708.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221848.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221848.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221854.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221854.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221948.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221948.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221955.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221955.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/14/wild-swim.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/14/wild-swim.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Piz Badile South Ridge</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;approach&quot;&gt;Approach&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;From Bagni Masino follow signs to Gianetti hut. From the the Gianetti hut traces of a path (ciarns) meander over small firm rocks and moraine in a northerly direction up to the buttress foot of the ridge.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;route&quot;&gt;Route&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;Keep L(W) of the moraine and rocks extending down from the ridge and cross snow patches at the right side of the small glacier in the bay below the col del badile.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;rise a short distance above the level of the ridge foot proper and turn in close to it, finding a gangway slanting from left to right across the west side of the buttress.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Ascend gangway to crest and pass onto east side.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;scramble along easy ledges overhung by jutting rocks, leftwards up into a steep chimney (III) which leads into the crest.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;follow a system of narrow ledges below crest on the east side again, into a broad open couloir that merges higher up into the face of the mountain climbing in the trough ahead, almost anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;finnish by one of two little parellel gullies on the summit ridge, about 40m west of the cairn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;descent&quot;&gt;Descent&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Go down the gully trough and take the ledge system on E side of the ridge.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Just before reaching the percipitous step of the terminal buttress turn sharp right (W) and pass over a little spur to find the gang way slanting down the west side of the buttress to snow at its foot.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The penalty for missing this turning is two long and uncomfortble abseils down a gritty ice gulley.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/topo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;topo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are loads of ciarns around the Gianetti hut so following them on approach is not very straight forward. On the plus side the start of the route is easy to spot so walking in the general direction will get you where you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The starting ramp was not obvious. We headed past the foot of the buttress towards a prominent crack we thought looked climbable, luckily the ramp starts near the base of the crack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fixed rope in the grade III chimney is worn to the core so be wary, after the chimney you climb up for a short while before heading right on to the ledges (thin paths). This right turn is easy to miss… After a while the ledges become really thin and transform into about 15m of unprotectable scrambling, there is a fixed rope here which is a good route marker but is extremely worn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In descent the top of this fixed rope there is a mallion and plenty of good abseil tat, at the top of the grade III chimney the cross and another rock provide an abseil point to the right of the chimney (if facing towards the base). This leads to the top of the “climbable crack” and a nice big ring anchor which will allow you to abseil to the start of the route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus points if you find a chocolate bar wedged in a crack while abseiling…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rack&quot;&gt;Rack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Half set of nuts, even numbers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 slings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 alpine draws&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;single 60m rope&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;usual locking biners, tat, belay devices…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/racking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Racking up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/badTurn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not a good start&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/worthIt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;worth it!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/14/badile-south.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/14/badile-south.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
