<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Choss Bucket</title>
    <description>Just some climbing in Europe</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 12:51:26 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 12:51:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vergine-Al Gal Uberschreitung</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/vergineAlGal/IMG_20150831_195022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/vergineAlGal/IMG_20150831_195131.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/vergineAlGal/IMG_20150831_195151.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/vergineAlGal/IMG_20150831_195944.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teils solite am halblangen seil gekiettert werden konnen&lt;br /&gt;
um die Gratpassagen sinnvoll schern zu konnen.&lt;br /&gt;
Teils gebohrt (saniert Bobbi Gotte 1998);&lt;br /&gt;
Klemmkeile, Friends und Schlingen zusatzlich sind ratsum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absteig: Normalerweise wird uber den Sudgrat des Al Gal&lt;br /&gt;
abgeklettert. Stellen bis 3a und eine Abseilstelle von 25m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part should be climbed at half-long rope can&lt;br /&gt;
the Gratpassagen exchangers useful to be able to .&lt;br /&gt;
Drilled portion ( rehabilitated Bobbi God 1998) ;&lt;br /&gt;
Chocks , Friends and snares are advised additionally .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Descend : Normally via the south ridge of Al Gal&lt;br /&gt;
downclimb . Set up a 3a and abseil 25m&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/vergine-al-gal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/vergine-al-gal.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Usefull Translations</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;bh&quot;&gt;4BH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Modern bohrhakenmaterial steckt in sehr kursen Abstanden. Solche Gebiete eignen sich auch fur erste Vorstiegsversuche von Angfangern und fur Kinder. es werden nur Expressschlingen benotigt.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(PLaisirstandard: super, kids)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bh-1&quot;&gt;2BH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Modern bohrhakenmaterial stekt in zeitgemassen Abstanden. Schlusselstellen sind gut abgsichert. Langere Abstande zwinschen den Sicherungspunkten sind aber in leichteren Passagen in der entsprechenden Route ublich.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(PLaisirstandard: super, gut)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bh--1-keil&quot;&gt;2BH / 1 Keil&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Modern bohrhakenmaterial stekt in zeitgemassen bstanden. Schlusselstellen sind gut abgsichert. Langere Abstande zwinschen den Sicherungspunkten sind aber in leichteren Passagen in der entsprechenden Route ublich. In alpinen Routen empfiehlt sich zusatzliche die Mitnahme einiger mobiler Sicherungsmittel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(PLaisirstandard: gut)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bh--1-keil-1&quot;&gt;1 BH / 1 Keil&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Modernes, teils auch Älteres bohrhakenmaterial stekt in oft weiten abstÄnden. Der Vorstieger sollte den. Schwierigkeitsgrad beherrschen und grosse erfahrung haben. bei rissen ist oft keine fixe absicherung vorhanden und die zusatzliche mitnahme verschiedenartiger mobiler Sicherungsmittel ist notig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(PLaisirstandard: so… so.., Alpin)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern , partly mature bolts stekt in often long distances . The lead climber should the . Difficulty dominate and have great experience . If cracks is often no fixed protection available and the additional driving different types of mobile backup means and experience dictate .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bh-2&quot;&gt;1 BH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Modernes bohrhakenmaterial stekt oft in weiten abstanden. der Vorstieger sollte den Schwierigkeitsgrad beherrschen und grosse erfahrung haben. in alpinen Routen dieser katagorie ist das legen von mobilen Sicherungsmitteln oft nicht moglich und langere runouts lassen sich nicht vermeiden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(PLaisirstandard: so… so.., expo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ring&quot;&gt;Ring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altes oder schlechtes bohrhakenmaterial. die Abstande entsprechen dem zeitgeist der Erschliessung und sind oft gross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PLaisirstandart: so.. so.., Alpin oder expo)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keil--friends&quot;&gt;Keil / Friends&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaum fixe Sicherungen in der route. die kletterei muss komplett selber abgesichert werden. Ein umfangreiches Alpin-rack ist notig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;normalhaken&quot;&gt;Normalhaken&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die route weisst nur klassische Normalhaken auf. ein einschatzen der festigkeit ist auch fur experten nicht einfach und das mitfuhren eines hammers ware empfehlenswert. in alpinen routen ist die zusatzliche mitnahmen verschiedenartiger mobiler sicherungsmittel notig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(PLaisirstandard: Alpin)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;achtung&quot;&gt;Achtung!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sehr gefahrliche route ohne naturliche absicherungsmoglichkeiten, auch in schwersten stellen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;technisch-gekletterte-route&quot;&gt;Technisch gekletterte Route&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kaumfixe absicherungen und fort bewegungspunkte vorhanden. diverses technomaterial wie alle arten von haken, cliffs, copperheads, usw. sind notig.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/usefull-translations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/usefull-translations.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gemelli Bugeleisen</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/gemelli-bugeleisen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/01/gemelli-bugeleisen.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Little Micheluzzi</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;aproach&quot;&gt;Aproach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start 10m left of the gully which splits the face, at the base of an easy ramp leading right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;route&quot;&gt;Route&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III&lt;/strong&gt;, 30m. Follow the series of ledges right (beware of seepage).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II&lt;/strong&gt;, 15m. Continue right to a stance at the base of a chimney.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III+&lt;/strong&gt;, 25m. Climb the chimney then move right to a vegetated clearing. Move left then direct up a series of gravel terraces and move behind a boulder to a ring belay.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II&lt;/strong&gt;, 50m. Continue leftwards up a blocky and somewhat loose ramp, passing below a large crack to a stance on a good ledge.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III&lt;/strong&gt;, 25m. Climb a narrow chimney before moving left over ledges. Move right again to a stance below a large grassy ramp on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V-&lt;/strong&gt;, 45. Ignore the grassy ramp and instead climb direct to a belay ring then traverse right on good holds. Continue more direct, still on excellent rock with plenty of gear before following the logical traverse right to a yellow niche. Belay on the right side of the cave. An excellent pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IV&lt;/strong&gt;, 30m. Exit the cave on the right, following the red arrow which points around the corner. Route finding becomes slightly harder here but follow the worn holds direct, then right for a few metres, before climbing direct again to another yellow cave (possible stance). Pass this and move left to the belay.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IV&lt;/strong&gt;, 35m. Step left from the stance and move left to a series of chimney-cracks. Climb the middle of the three (although all three variants are possible) on good holds to reach the terraces below the Chamois Terrace. Belay in a small cave.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/26/little-Micheluzzi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/26/little-Micheluzzi.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nobs Adventures</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So our amazing friend Naomi and her lovely boyfriend Bob are traveling through Europe in their green adventure van, wild swimming their way from France to Italy and back again. We were going to try and meet up but it just so happened that our favourite town val masino was about a 30 min walk from one of the swims Naomi wanted to do the most. They arrived on an unfortunatley rainy day and after admiring each other vans and talking about the complexties of gas and solar we hid away at the local cafe. It did stop raining in the late afternoon so we decided to make a break for it and walk up to val d’mello where there is an amazing wild swimming spot. The boy and I had already been up there for a bit of an explore and it was ridiculously cold - glacial melt - but we didnt swim for long as there were loads of people about - noone else swimming and we felt like a bit of a spectacle. And we were cold.&lt;br /&gt;
Because we had walked up in big jackets we were pretty warm when we got there and because it had rained quite a lot in the last 24 hours the water was a (sort of) bareable temperature. We had quite a long swim, by val masino standards but it was still pretty chilly. Naomi has been bloggin their wild swim adventures and I’ve nicked one of her photos, see the rest of the blog here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got out it started to rain and the rain turned into a pretty heavy thunderstorm which meant we all got quite wet, again. Back at the vans we dried off and pulled up door to door. Very cosy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/17/Nobs-Adventures.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/17/Nobs-Adventures.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wild Swimming In Italy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221404.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221404.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221424.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221424.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221431.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221431.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221502.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221502.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221520.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221520.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221541.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221541.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221601.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221601.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221648.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221648.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221701.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221701.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221708.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221708.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221848.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221848.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221854.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221854.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221948.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221948.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221955.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wildSwim/IMG_20150814_221955.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/14/wild-swim.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/14/wild-swim.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Piz Badile South Ridge</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;approach&quot;&gt;Approach&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;From Bagni Masino follow signs to Gianetti hut. From the the Gianetti hut traces of a path (ciarns) meander over small firm rocks and moraine in a northerly direction up to the buttress foot of the ridge.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;route&quot;&gt;Route&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;Keep L(W) of the moraine and rocks extending down from the ridge and cross snow patches at the right side of the small glacier in the bay below the col del badile.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;rise a short distance above the level of the ridge foot proper and turn in close to it, finding a gangway slanting from left to right across the west side of the buttress.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Ascend gangway to crest and pass onto east side.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;scramble along easy ledges overhung by jutting rocks, leftwards up into a steep chimney (III) which leads into the crest.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;follow a system of narrow ledges below crest on the east side again, into a broad open couloir that merges higher up into the face of the mountain climbing in the trough ahead, almost anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;finnish by one of two little parellel gullies on the summit ridge, about 40m west of the cairn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;descent&quot;&gt;Descent&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Go down the gully trough and take the ledge system on E side of the ridge.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Just before reaching the percipitous step of the terminal buttress turn sharp right (W) and pass over a little spur to find the gang way slanting down the west side of the buttress to snow at its foot.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;The penalty for missing this turning is two long and uncomfortble abseils down a gritty ice gulley.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/topo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;topo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are loads of ciarns around the Gianetti hut so following them on approach is not very straight forward. On the plus side the start of the route is easy to spot so walking in the general direction will get you where you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The starting ramp was not obvious. We headed past the foot of the buttress towards a prominent crack we thought looked climbable, luckily the ramp starts near the base of the crack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fixed rope in the grade III chimney is worn to the core so be wary, after the chimney you climb up for a short while before heading right on to the ledges (thin paths). This right turn is easy to miss… After a while the ledges become really thin and transform into about 15m of unprotectable scrambling, there is a fixed rope here which is a good route marker but is extremely worn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In descent the top of this fixed rope there is a mallion and plenty of good abseil tat, at the top of the grade III chimney the cross and another rock provide an abseil point to the right of the chimney (if facing towards the base). This leads to the top of the “climbable crack” and a nice big ring anchor which will allow you to abseil to the start of the route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus points if you find a chocolate bar wedged in a crack while abseiling…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rack&quot;&gt;Rack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Half set of nuts, even numbers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 slings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 alpine draws&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;single 60m rope&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;usual locking biners, tat, belay devices…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/racking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Racking up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/badTurn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not a good start&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pizBadileSouth/worthIt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;worth it!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/14/badile-south.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/14/badile-south.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Punta Della Sfinge via Bramani</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;5i) for the NE wall (via Bramani). - [Climbers] 1931&lt;br /&gt;
Salt sinstra edge path from fiorelli away, along a succession of corners and crevices. excellent rock. Enough accompanying repeated. Development: 250m. Difficulty: II / IV. Material: nut and friend up to # 2. Attack: far right wall, near a whitish plaque at the base of the corner.&lt;br /&gt;
Itinerary: you climb to a whitish plaque machined down to a slit. Climb it and go on to plates and broken rocks up to a dihedral. climb to the crackline and achieve a specroncino; go up it and continue for plates up to a ledge. the original route follows the ledge to the left and continues to steps and plates more easily to the summit. Today, however, if it goes straight to placchete and blades until it meets the road Fiorelli. Equip stops with belays. In a few nails on. Descent: abseil on the road (belays droppie x 40m).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/sfinge1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawn topo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/sfinge2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo topo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aproach&quot;&gt;Aproach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Park at Bagni Masino past the hotel/spa in the trees. Follow the track to until reaching signposts for rifugi Omio, take the right hand path labeled 2hrs. The path is marked with red/white/red paint all the way to the hut. After reaching rifugi Omio a small path up the hill and left of the hut towards the P.do Ligoncio, 1.5hrs again marked with red/white/red paint. The Sfinge will become visible and a large painted sign will advise when to divert from the path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the start of the route towards the right of the face, a short scramble leads to a long layback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;route&quot;&gt;Route&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved together stopping at rappel stations to belay and recover gear. 2hrs45mins from base to summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P1&lt;/strong&gt;; follow the lay back crack to a bolt, then trend left over flakes towards a large ring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p2&lt;/strong&gt;; follow the groove and flakes upwards towards another large ring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p3&lt;/strong&gt;; continue on flakes untill a left trend takes you through a slight overhanging chimney, head right towards a layback reaching the next ring shortly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p4&lt;/strong&gt;; continue on the flakes untill reaching a ledge which can rises leftwards untill it meets a groove trending right. follow to ring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p5&lt;/strong&gt;; we climbed up and right briefly skirting a different face of the mountain on an easy but exposed ramp, this lead to a gulley and to a bolt near the summit. Had we climbed left and into a groove we would have found the last ring of the type used for other belays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;descent&quot;&gt;Descent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we abseiled back down the face. Our final bolt lead to an Abseil ring a few meters below. From this point each bolt was spaced aproximatly 40 meters apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rack&quot;&gt;Rack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50m half ropes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;set of nuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cams 1-3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 alpine draws&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 slings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;locking biners, prusiks, tat, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/up to the hut_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mid slog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/IMG_20150730_162137.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tilly the refuge dog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/cafe soup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;coffee soup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/wanderer_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bivi spot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/punta della sfinge_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;view of sfinge on aproach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/effect-express1438699304880.png&quot; alt=&quot;moving up the first pitch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/bums and feet_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mid way on the sfinge: bramini&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/IMG_20150803_122259.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;view from the summit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/effect-express1438699196120.png&quot; alt=&quot;summit selfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/effect-express1438699114021.png&quot; alt=&quot;ab off&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sfinge/vanAndMistyMountains_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;van spot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/07/sfinge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/07/sfinge.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A cheapskates guide to Val Masino</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We stopped near San Martino. Water fountains are everywhere, free parking is to be found between most of the little villages though no one seems to check the tickets on the other car parks any way. There are public toilets by the main sport climbing area. There is a reasonable internet connection at Bar Monica and they have guide books you can read while you have a drink. Also a small shop for food but it is quite pricey so stock up on non-perishables elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not possible to buy a guide book in english at the local climbing shop so I’d bring one with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some topos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150726_153607.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150726_153801.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150729_150446.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150804_193115.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150804_193120.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150804_193126.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150805_110039.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150805_110128.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150805_154700.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150805_154718.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150805_184630.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150805_184644.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150806_103948.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/valMasinoTopos/IMG_20150806_103958.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/07/cheapskates-guide-to-Val-Masino.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/07/cheapskates-guide-to-Val-Masino.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reccy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Uuurrgh. We ache. We want to climb the Sfinge, and as it’s our first proper mountain we thought it would be a good idea to do a reccy up to the base, or near the base of the climb, especially as it’s unclear from a guide we translated with google whether we need crampons or not for the approach. A good idea, no? In theory yes, however we took the wrong turn immediately at the base of the valley, somehow following the faded old sign that said Omio (that’s the hut) 5.5 hours instead of the shiny new one directly above it which said Omio 3 hours. We followed an increasingly overgrown path punctuated by red dots of optimism that were secretly leading us astray. Our feet were so wet from the dew on the plants encroaching on the path that when crossing streams we resorted to just taking our shoes off and going along in socks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reccy/IMG_20150730_111710.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;stream crossing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then came across a herd of mountain goats about 20 meters away from us and thought they looked pretty cute. We were wrong. They proceeded to chase us for what felt like a very long time, and trying to run when already tired and with a heavy backpack was pretty difficult. There are no photos of the goats as it would have been far too dangerous to stop, have you seen their horns? After we thought we had pretty much got away from the goats we realised we were quite lost and thought we would see if anyone was living at this little shepherd’s hut (how he got his shopping up there I’ll never know). When we approached the house two dogs came racing and barking at us which was fairly terrifying. The shepherd appeared and called off the dogs and between his non-exsistant English and our dismal Italian it transpired that we needed to go…up. So we set off through some spikey undergrowth and eventually ended up wading and climbing upstream. Usually the kind of thing I’d enjoy but given the demon goats, killer dogs and being pretty lost we were pretty emotionally and physically done for! We did make it to the hut in the end and dried our socks and had huge bowls of latte, odd but needed, with several sugars!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reccy/IMG_20150730_141812.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drying socks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also met Tilly, the mountain dog who was very friendly and came to sit with us and enjoy the views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reccy/IMG_20150730_162137.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tilly the mountain dog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy went on to see if we need crampons and luckily we don’t, and we found the right path to get us back to chossy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/02/reccy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/08/02/reccy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
